(951)216-1122

TEMECULA CA

Overview

 Software Engineer in Test with proven success in developing manual and automated software test solutions for specialty insurance, healthcare / senior care solutions, clinical experiments, statistical analysis, and LIMS (Laboratory Information Management System)

 Provide Cross-discipline and cross-functional support through SDLC for senior care or health care industry applications

Software Engineer in Test Experience

- Testing, hardware and software requirements gathering and evaluation of web applications, LIMS (Laboratory Information Management System) and instrumentation/imaging systems (.NET/C#)
- Language experience: JavaScript, C#, CSS, Java, C++
- Database experience: MongoDB and MS SQL server.
- Selenium WebDriver with C# (MSTest / NUnit with SpecFlow) or Java (JUnit)
- JavaScript UI test:
 - Cypress test
 - DarlekJS
 - puppeteer.js, cucumber.js and chai
 - Ember.js Acceptance test
- General project management tool: JIRA, TFS, Azure DevOps
- General test tool: TestRail, Trello and TestPad

Professional Experience

Software Developer in Test American Specialty Health, Inc.

2017 – Present

chao.kuo@gmail.com

- Develop test automation following behavior-driven development process to facilitate cooperation between product owner, developer and testers
 - Cypress test for browser application with Codeship from CloudBees
 - o Selenium WebDriver with C#, MSTest and SpecFlow in CD/CI (VSTS)
- Create and manage product backlog item (PBI) on Team Foundation Server to enable non-blocking workflow with Scrum process
- Train manual testers to draft BDD style test feature files for SpecFlow to encourage knowledge sharing with Gherkin language
- Performance test and Load test with visual studio enterprise or JMeter to handle up to more than 1 million concurrent user
- Postman Web API test in JavaScript and integration with VSTS CD/CI pipeline
- UI test with Node.js application like puppeteer.js, cucumber.js and chai
- Ember.js Acceptance test with BDD addon (ember-cli-yadda)

Software QA Lead / Software QA Engineer

GreatCall, Inc. 2015 – 2017

• Develop black and white box testing strategies and test automation framework:

- Selenium WebDriver with C# (NUnit with SpecFlow option)
- o Test harness via Web API
- Work with stakeholders to very acceptance criteria and test coverage. Create, track, and reproduce software issues reports in designated defect tracking System (Zephyr for JIRA).
- Compile, update, execute/automate regression test plan for ecommerce web application
- Support cross-functional teams: Frontend and Backend Developers, Product Managers, third party vendors and other QA groups
- Develop frontend view and model modification for shopping cart workflow with JavaScript, CSS and HTML in ASP.NET MVC project
- Manual mobile App and embedded devices test
- Coordinate and delegate QA effort across functional groups for efficient test execution

Software Engineer/Test Engineer

AltheaDx 2014 – 2015

- Define, verify and review LIMS requirements with end users (Clinical Laboratory Scientists) against regulation standard such as ICD-9-CM Diagnosis and Procedure Codes
- Execute manual / automated test (with Java), record and validate software systems behaviors and generated reports to prevent regression
- Data-Driven Test with genetic data (with Java)
- Develop SQL queries to verify specific genotype and/or patient data
- Develop training library with version control and WIKI in SharePoint / TFS.
- Instrumentation of software with C# with Debug and Trace class

Associate Scientist / Instrument Specialist

Millennium Laboratories, Rancho Bernardo, CA

2012 - 2016

- Review and trouble-shoot LC-MS-MS data and instrumentation for specialty physicians.
- Develop C# script for data analysis automation

Research and Development Scientist

K.C. Pharmaceuticals, Pomona, CA

2012

- HPLC method development for pharmaceutical active ingredients for QC purpose
- Compile SOP for GMP production practice.

Analytical Chemist

Huntington Medical Research Institute, Pasadena, CA

2011-2012

• Developed Multiple Reaction Monitoring (MRM) method for over 50 fatty acid

Research Associate

Siemens medical solution diagnostic (US), Los Angeles, CA

2006-2010

- Up-Scale R&D samples, validated protein concentration and reactivity of biotinylated allergens samples with EXCEL programing
- Usability test and troubleshooting imaging system with software developer.
- Program TECAN instrument for assay automation.

MSDS Excel database management

Custom Environmental Services, Santa Barbara

2006

Managed, archived and updated MSDS database to FDA standard for Proctor and

Gamble facility in Oxnard, CA.

Language: Speaks and writes fluent Chinese

EDUCATION:

<u>University of California, Santa Barbara</u> B.S., Chemistry, March 2006

Palomar College, San Marcos

A.A., Computer Science, September 2014

References – available upon request